[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：JavaScript中的一切都是一个对象，所以数字，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Everything in JavaScript is an object, so numbers,
布尔值，字符串，数组，日期，正则表达式和函数，
booleans, strings, arrays, dates, regular expressions and functions,
它们都是物体。
they're all objects.
所以，让我们看看数字，数字是对象，它是一个简单得多的数字
So, let's look at numbers, numbers are objects, it's a much a simpler number
系统比Java中的要好，因为我们没有整数和整数，
system than you have in Java in that we don't have ints and integers,
这两个都没有，你只有数字。
you don't have either of those, you just have numbers.
我们用数字文字做数字。
We make numbers with number literals.
所有这些数字文字都引用同一个对象。
All these number literals refer to the same object.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：JavaScript中只有一种数字类型，即
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: There's only one number type in JavaScript which is
实际上，这是一件非常好的事情，没有整数类型
actually a very good thing and there are no integer types which is something you
必须习惯，但这其实也是一件好事。
have to get used to but it's actually a good thing too.
问题是我们拥有的一个数字类型是错误的。
The problem is that the one number type we have is the wrong one.
它基于IEEE-754标准中的64位二进制浮点
It's based on 64-bit binary floating point from the IEEE-754 standard
在Java和其他语言中被奇怪地称为Double。
which is strangely called double in Java and other languages.
有人想知道为什么叫双倍吗？
Anybody care to know why it's called double?
为什么他们选择了这样一个愚蠢的名字？
Why they picked such a silly name?
这是来自Fortran的东西。
It's something that comes from Fortran.
Fortran有整数和实数，后来又增加了双精度，
Fortran had integer and real and later they added double precision,
这两个雷亚尔放在一起是为了给你更高的精确度。
which was two reals put together in order to give you more precision.
C采用Fortran的双精度，并将其缩短为双精度。
And C took Fortran's double precision and shortened it to double.
从那以后，其他人都在使用Double。
And everyone else has been using double ever since then.
所以我们没有整型，我很高兴我们没有整型，因为我讨厌整型。
So we don't have ints and I'm glad we don't have ints cuz I hate ints.
int有一些非常奇怪的属性。
Ints have some really strange properties.
例如，我们可以有两个INT，它们都大于零。
For example, we can have two ints which are both greater than zero.
我们可以把它们加在一起，我们可以得到更小的结果
We can add them together and we can get results that are smaller
比原来的数字，这是疯狂的和不可原谅的，以及如何可以
than the original numbers, which is insane and inexcusable, and how can
你对你的系统的正确性和完美性有信心
you have any confidence in the correctness and the perfection of your system
如果它是建立在一个可以做如此荒唐可笑的事情的数字类型上的话？
if it's built on a number type which can do such insanely ridiculous things?
所以JavaScript没有这个缺点，我认为这是很棒的。
So JavaScript does not have this defect in it which I think is brilliant.
所以一般计算机算术的一个问题
So one problem with computer arithmetic in general
结合法是不能成立的，那是因为
is that the Associative Law will not hold, and that's because
计算机数字必然是有限的，而实数不一定是有限的。
computer numbers are necessarily finite and real numbers aren't.
所以在很多情况下，我们只处理近似。
So in many cases we're only dealing with approximations.
当这些值是近似值时，结合性就不成立了。
And when the values are approximate, then associativity doesn't hold.
现在如果你只局限于整数空间，
Now if you just confine to the integer space,
JavaScript整数上升到大约9千万亿，这是相当大的。
JavaScript integers go up to around 9 quadrillion, which is pretty big.
9千万亿比国债还大，所以它很大，对吧？
9 quadrillion is bigger than the national debt, so it's big, right?
这可是大事。
That's big.
所以只要你的整数小于9千万亿，它们就能精确地计算出来。
So as long as your integers are smaller than 9 quadrillion they work out exactly.
当整数达到9千万亿以上时，它们不会做疯狂的环绕
When the integers get above 9 quadrillion they don't do the crazy wrap around
INT做的事情，他们只是变得模糊。
thing that ints do, they just get fuzzy.
所以如果我取一个大于9千万亿的数字并加上1，这就像我
So if I take a number above 9 quadrillion and add 1 to it, it's like I
向其添加0，这不是很好，但它比INT所做的要好得多。
added 0 to it, which is not good but it's much less bad than what ints do.
并且因为计算机算法可以是近似的，
And because computer arithmetic can be approximate,
然后还有一些我们习惯于思考的身份，而这些身份是不能成立的。
then there are identities that we're used to thinking about which don't hold.
所以你需要意识到这一点并保持谨慎。
So you need to be aware of that and cautious.
因此，JavaScript最常报告的bug是0.10+0.20不等于0.30。
So the most reported bug for JavaScript is that 0.10 + 0.20 is not equal to 0.30.
这是因为我们试图表示小数
And that's because we're trying to represent decimal fractions
在二进制浮点中。
in binary floating point.
并且二进制浮点不能准确地表示
And binary floating point cannot accurately represent
大多数小数分数。
most of the decimal fractions.
它只能近似它们，但它用无限近似它们
It can only approximate them, but it approximates them with infinite
重复位模式，但我们不允许有无限长的数字。
repeating bit patterns, but we're not allowed to have infinitely long numbers.
所以它们被截断，所以每个数字都会略有错误。
And so they truncate, and so every number is gonna be slightly wrong.
这只是一个问题，如果你生活在一个使用十进制系统的星球上。
Which is only a problem if you're living on a planet that uses the decimal system.
但是在这样一个星球上，你用这个来计算人们的钱。
But on such a planet, you're counting people's money using this.
当你加别人的钱时，
When you're adding people's money,
他们有一个合理的期望，你会得到正确的金额。
they have a reasonable expectation you're gonna get the right sum.
我们不能保证用二进制浮点得到正确的和，
And we're not guaranteed to get the right sum with binary floating point,
这是个大问题。
which is a huge problem.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：数字是对象，所以数字有方法。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Numbers are objects, and so numbers have methods.
你不必为了获得对象行为而对它们进行装箱。
You don't have to box them in order to get object behavior.
每个数字都已经是一个对象。
Every number is already an object.
每个数字都是从Number.Prototype继承而来的。
Every number inherits from number.prototype.
所以如果我们想要给数字添加新的方法，
So if we wanted to add new methods to numbers,
我们可以通过将它们添加到Number.Prototype来做到这一点。
we can do that by adding them to number.prototype.
这不是应用程序应该做的事情，但它是有用的
This is not something that applications should ever do, but it is a useful
库要做的事情，事实上这就是我们如何发展语言。
thing for libraries to do, and in fact this is how we evolve the language.
因此我们可以将新方法添加到新版本的标准和
So we can add new methods to new versions of the standard and
库可以回填旧的浏览器和旧的实现
libraries can back fill old browsers, and old implementations
只要可以用JavaScript实现新的方法，就可以使用新的东西。
with the new stuff as long as new methods can be implemented in JavaScript.
数字是第一类对象，这意味着数字可以存储在
Numbers are first class objects which means that a number can be stored in
变量，可以作为参数传递，可以从函数返回，并且
a variable, can be passed as a parameter, can be returned from a function and
它可以存储在对象中。
it can be stored in an object.
因为数字本身就是对象，所以它们可以有方法。
And because numbers are themselves objects they can have methods.
JavaScript在使用单独的数学时犯了与Java相同的错误
JavaScript has made the same mistake that Java made in having a separate math
对象或数学容器，用于保持较高的
object or math container for keeping the higher
初等函数。
elementary functions.
这是在Java中完成的，预计未来可能会非常低
This was done in Java anticipating that in the future there might be very low
内存配置，他们希望能够删除数学函数。
memory configurations and they'd wanna be able to remove the math functions.
这并没有发生，因为摩尔定律一直在影响记忆容量，所以
That didn't happen because Moore's Law kept cranking on memory capacity so
事实证明，这并不是一个好的策略。
that turned out not to have been a good strategy.
但它无论如何都不会起作用，因为你会丢弃必要的东西
But it wouldn't have worked anyway because you'd be throwing away essential things
比如地板。
like floor.
没有好的方法可以获得的整数部分
There's no good way to get the integer part of
一个数字，如果你去掉了楼层函数，所以它不可能工作。
a number if you get rid of the floor function so it couldn't have worked.
数学对象中也存储了一些常量。
There are also some constants stored in the math object as well.
所以，最糟糕的一件事，或者是我们从
So, one of the worst, or one of the things that we get from
IEEE格式是一种称为NaN的格式，它代表的不是数字。
the IEEE format is something called NaN, which stands for Not a Number.
这是混淆或错误操作的结果。
It's the result of confusing or erroneous operations.
例如，如果你试图用零除以零，结果是NaN。
For example, if you're trying to divide zero by zero the result is NaN.
NaN是有毒的，这意味着以NaN作为输入的任何算术运算
NaN is toxic, which means that any arithmetic operation with NaN as an input
将NaN作为输出。
will have NaN as an output.
尽管NaN代表的不是一个数字，但它是一个数字。
And despite the fact that NaN stands for Not a Number, it is a number.
如果你问JavaScript，NaN的类型是什么？
If you ask JavaScript, what is the type of NaN?
它说的是数字，它是对的。
It says number and it's right.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我讨厌NaN的一点是，NaN不等于
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The thing I hate about NaN is that NaN is not equal to
包括NaN在内的任何东西，所以NaN等于NaN是假的。
anything including NaN, so NaN equal NaN is false.
让我下地狱的虫子
Which bugs the hell out of me and
更糟糕的是，NaN不等于NaN是真的。
even worse than that is that NaN not equal NaN is true.
我更讨厌这一点。
Which I hate even more.
因此，如果你想知道某个东西是否是NaN，有一个全局isNaN函数。
So if you want to find out if something is NaN, there is a global isNaN function.
你可以把NaN传递给它，它会返回true，这很好。
And you can pass NaN to it and it will return true, which is good.
不幸的是，isNaN也执行类型强制。
Unfortunately, isNaN also does type coercion.
所以如果你向它传递一个类似hello world的字符串，
So if you pass it a string like hello world,
它会尝试将字符串转换为数字。
it'll try to convert the string into a number.
hello world变成的号码是NaN，所以
The number that hello world turns into is NaN, so
你好，世界是南，这不是真的。
hello world is NaN, which is not true.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以自从Fortran以来，我们一直在写声明
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So ever since Fortran, we've been writing statements
看起来像这样，x=x+1，这是数学上的废话。
that look like this, x = x + 1, which is mathematical nonsense.
所以Algol做对了
So ALGOL got this right.
Algol想出了一个赋值运算符，这样看起来就不那么可笑了，而且
ALGOL came up with an assignment operator so this didn't look so ridiculous, and
BCPL做了和ALGOL相同的事情，这是正确的。
BCPL did the same thing as ALGOL which got it right.
不幸的是汤普森更喜欢这个
Unfortunately Thompson liked this better,
所以我们又回到了它，从那以后我们再也没有进化过。
and so we reverted back to it and we have not evolved away from this since.
所以我们被困在这看起来很疯狂，对吧？
So we're stuck with this and it looks crazy, right?
因为它看起来像一个方程式，但是
Because it looks like an equation but
没有等于x+1的x的值。
there's no value of x which equals x + 1 right.
但是如果你使用的是二进制浮点，
Except it turns out if you're using binary floating point,
有一个值叫做无穷大。
there's a value called infinity.
如果你把1加到无穷大，你就得到了无穷大，所以这实际上是一个等式。
And, if you add one to infinity, you get infinity so this actually is an equation.
有一个值X，这是真的。
There is a value of X for which this is true.
不仅如此，还有一个名为Number.MAX_VALUE的值
And not just that, there's another value called Number.MAX_VALUE
这是一个后面跟着308位数字的数字，这真是一个很大的数字。
which is one followed by 308 digits, that's a really big number.
如果你在JavaScript知道的最大数字上加一，你会认为
And if you add one to the biggest number that JavaScript knows you would think that
将是无穷大，但它不是，它将是MAX_VALUE，所以它成立。
would be infinity but it isn't it, it'll be MAX_VALUE, so it holds.
事实上，对于9千万亿以上的每个数字都是如此。
In fact that is true for every number above 9 quadrillion.
所以这里面有很多值。
So there's a lot of values for which this holds.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：但不是NaN。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But not NaN.
即使NaN加一是NaN，NaN也不等于NaN。
Even though NaN plus one is NaN, NaN is not equal to NaN.
所以我讨厌那个，南，我更讨厌那个。
So I hate that and NaN, I hate that even more.